Hey there.
>> Hey there.
>> I'm Ted R and I'm here for a D program
along with John Kuryaku. Uh he's the CIA
whistleblower. I'm the editorial
cartoonist. Uh thank you so much for
joining us. It's Wednesday, July 30th,
2025. It's 5:00 PM on the East Coast.
Thanks for joining us on the Rumble
feed, on the YouTube feed, and
everywhere else you're listening also to
uh people just listening to the audio.
We appreciate you, too. Please like,
follow, and share the show. Lots to talk
about today, as always. Um, we talked
about that this might happen, John. I I
didn't think it would happen this fast.
>> No way.
>> The UK is almost certainly going to
recognize Palestine at the UN General
Assembly this September. Well, that's
our lead. Uh we're going to be talking
about u interesting news out of Iran
where Iran's leading the way in
abandoning US tech, namely GPS. And uh
you know, we could see a lot more of
this kind of thing coming in the very
near future from all over the world. Um
super interesting uh look into the
future. Um is Israel losing the American
right? The evangelicals who've been
their loyal supporters. Marjorie Taylor
Green is criticizing the Gaza war as
genocide. She's right, of course, but
it's amazing to hear her and people like
her saying anything like that. Um, two
CIA related stories that there's no way
I'm going to let you off the hook, John,
from talking about. Tom Sylvester is out
at the CIA and uh Sandy Grimes, the lady
who caught Aldrich Ames, died at the age
of 80. We'll talk about her legacy and
we'll talk about breaking news and
anything else that comes up. And of
course, if you have questions, please
put them into uh the feeds and we always
pick up on them and post them and talk
about them. But uh we've got lots of
stuff to talk about. So Kirst um he kind
of like gave it kind of give some people
are interpreting this as a wussy move
but he basically said he'll recognize
Palestine uh in September unless uh
Israel comes to its senses and agrees to
a ceasefire. They've been the ones
who've been breaking all the ceasefires
up until now. And um so you know
obviously Israel's not going to do that.
So, by definition, the UK will will join
France. And there's a whole pestle of
other countries who are interested in
doing it, too. So, let's get to it.
>> Yeah. Let's let's start, if you don't
mind, with Tom Sylvester.
>> Oh, thank you very much, Marble.
>> Let's do Tom Sylvester.
>> I just want to get this out of the way
because we have so much to talk about
related to uh to Gaza. Tom Sylvester is
the uh the CIA's deputy director for
operations. And in that position, he's
you can argue the number three or number
four U official in the CIA. He's in
charge of all CIA operations around the
world. This is a job that every CIA case
officer aspires to. Um and by all
accounts he's been very um popular uh
among the rank and file. Well, if you've
been the deputy director for operations,
your final pre-retirement job is
normally that you're named station chief
in London. That is the one job that
everybody in the CIA aspires to.
Everybody wants to be the station chief
in London. So he was named station chief
in London um several months ago,
but over the course of those several
months, he gave an interview to Tim uh
Weiner, who uh is the the Puliter
Prizewinning author of several books on
the CIA. Uh there's one coming out soon
called The Mission that um Thank you,
Eric.
that um several outlets are excerpting
and
apparently
CIA director John Radcliffe didn't like
the fact that he spoke with Tim Weiner.
Now, normally the director of the CIA
will instruct his officers to to work
with with authors, especially with Tim
Weiner. But whatever it is that Tom
Sylvester said, it apparently pissed
people off. And so the job was
unceremonious unceremoniously yanked
from under him. He will not be the CIA
station chief in chief in London. Uh,
Director Ratcliffe informed MI6
apparently yesterday that Sylvester will
not be the CIA station chief in London.
And so today, Sylvester announced his
retirement effective immediately. He's
just going to take his pension and go
home. Now,
most of the time,
senior officers, even if they're
disgruntled,
will keep their mouths shut. The fact
that he's already spoken to Tim Weiner
makes me think the story's not over.
We're gonna hear more. Uh so that's
that.
>> So my fathering
>> my father worked in government
specifically in the US Air Force for for
years at at the upper echelons and he
told me and John tell me if this is
correct that um usually when you know
you're about to retire that's your one
chance to vent and blow up. you know
you're going to retire anyway and you've
had stuff that you wanted to say. You've
got one big thing you want to do,
someone you want to blow up, some boss
who was an [__] and then this is when
you do it and then you you retire and
they can't get you. Is that basically
what what happened here?
>> 100%. 100%. And I I'll tell you my own
experience. My last tour
uh when I resigned from the agency was
at the United Nations in New York. And
um my station chief, Mary Margaret
Graham, and I did not like each other,
even not a little bit.
And so
a couple of days before I I left, she
threatened me. threatened me with with
putting out what's called a burn notice
against me.
>> Oh,
>> I saw that TV show.
>> Yeah, she she threatened me with a burn
notice and
I laughed at her. I was in her office
and of course she had her little witness
there, the chief of operations who was a
just a little dwarf. So, um
I said uh
I said I'm not afraid of your threats.
burn notice. I said, "Come on. You
forget that when I made this recent
recruitment,
you congratulated me me by telling me to
take petty cash and go get myself a
blowjob." I said, "What do you think the
Washington Post would say about that
>> or the New York Times? Because as God is
my witness, I'm gonna call them and tell
them."
>> And she immediately backed off.
>> Wow. So, uh,
>> by the way, I do want to answer, uh,
maybe you can't answer this question.
Um, Marble is asking, "Why is London a
desirable post?" It's like the top post,
right? It's the post
>> because you get a gigantic mansion to
live in. You get a chauffeur driven um,
uh, Jaguar limo that that they drive you
around in. You have the largest
entertainment budget of any station
chief in the world. Nobody's trying to
kill you there.
>> MI6 is the closest um alliance, right?
Intelligence that we have
>> without any question. MI6 CIA is the
closest friendship in the world.
>> So it's like it's analogous to in the
state department, right? Ambassador to
the court of St. James. It's the same
kind of thing. It's it's the job.
>> Yes. Exactly. Right. It is the job. I
mean,
>> it's like for an editorial cartoonist
like New York Times, you know, it's like
that,
>> right? And and so Hans, I absolutely
positively did not. I've never paid for
it in my life and I'm proud to say that.
So, although we all pay for it in
different ways, that's
>> nothing's free as my working girlfriends
used to tell me. But even at lower
levels in London, like I I did I I've
spoken about this operation I did with
Christopher Steel back in 2000 and my my
I was in Athens at the time, but I would
travel to London every week and then my
counterparts in the station um who were
you know just whatever GS12, GS13, GS14
uh they were living high on the hog too.
you're living in Nightsbridge
or you're living in in Paddington and
this beautiful uh muse house and life is
good and like I say people aren't trying
to kill you on the way to work.
>> Gotta love that.
>> Refreshing.
>> Um how by the way what do you what do
you think of uh Tom Sylvester and what
do you think of Tim Winer? Tim Weiner
Winer Weiner.
>> Um you know honestly I like them both.
Uh Tom Sylvester was a was an inspired
choice to be the deputy director for
operations. The guy's been he was a
station chief I don't know six times,
seven times all around the world. He was
a specialist in Soviet and then Russian
um operations and um and really
quite the good uh ops guy, careerlong
ops guy. Spent almost his entire adult
life overseas.
Uh Tim Weiner I actually have a great
deal of respect for. I gave him an
interview uh for his his previous book
about the CIA and he treated me with
great respect. So um I you know
>> I read that book. Yeah. It's a it's a
solid read for sure.
>> It's it's a solid read and and read and
it won the National Book Award which is
a very big deal.
>> Yeah.
>> Very big deal. I mean, it's it's
definitely not a fun read,
unfortunately. And I and that's my kind
of idea of a fun read, but
>> yeah, it doesn't, you know, I mean, I
love I mean, that's all I read is that
kind of thing. But
>> I love it.
>> Yeah. But I mean, the pros doesn't sing,
but I would say it's worth it's worth
>> a little bit on the dense side, but he
footnotes the daylights out of his
books.
>> I appreciate that.
>> He backs up everything he writes. It's
It's quite impressive. And then his
books are like 800 pages long.
>> Yeah. I mean, I'm a sucker for those
long books. Uh I've been hearing that
like uh word counts are dropping at
books. Like uh 100,000 120,000 words
used to be a standard like fiction book.
Now 60 or 80,000 is like closer to a
novella because people's attention span
is so short. But the biographies and and
political non-fiction still is the
outlier. They're getting longer and
longer all the time. Um
>> can I ask can I answer Eric um who real
quickly? Um Eric, the um the rule on the
Peace Corp was written in granite. There
could be no contact whatsoever
between the CIA and the Peace Corp for
several reasons. First of all, everybody
already accuses the Peace Corp being
CIA, right? So it's dangerous enough.
Secondly,
the Peace Corps has no protection.
They're out there in the sticks. You're
you you are out there in the sticks
doing God's work and there's nobody to
protect you. So, we were not permitted
to even like say hello if we ran into
somebody from the
>> good. I mean honestly that is a good
rule that you guys had because I mean
you know it's to me the analogy is the
uh journalism the journalist embedding
programs
>> without a doubt
>> violently opposed to um and you know
it's like the the as soon as that
started in Afghan in well in Iraq um
anytime you went anywhere you know the
the locals would say like well you're
just uh you know you're with the US
soldiers you're you know you're a
propagandist you're I can't trust you
why shouldn't I kill you and it's like I
mean It's so dangerous. And then, you
know, with a as a journalist, the only
weapon you have is your your camera or
your or your your laptop. I mean,
>> that's it. You're on your own.
>> You're really like your your dick is
waving out in the wind. I mean, it's
bad.
>> Yeah, it's bad.
>> Um, so, uh, do you want to talk do you
want to talk about do the others? Do you
want to do Sandy Grimes or should we
save her later?
>> Let's do Sandy Grimes. You know, Sandy
Grimes
Sandy Grimes is another kind of
legendary figure and she never really
set out to be. Um Sandy started off as a
secretary uh in the days when I think
she started back in ' 67 is what I read.
But those were the days when women were
not permitted to have leadership roles.
Not just leadership roles. They were not
permitted to really do anything of
import. They were only secretaries and
clerks, file clerks. So, she started off
as a secretary
and then rose up to be one of the the
greatest mole hunters in CIA's history.
And she's the one who caught Aldrich
Ames, one of the most despicable
traitors in modern American history. So,
u and she she was totally unsung. She
didn't. Even inside the building,
if you would say to somebody, "Hey, so
which one of these people over here is
Sandy Grimes?" Nobody would know because
she wasn't about the fanfare. Her job
was to find the mole. And by God, she
found him and he got life without
parole. I remember George Tennant saying
one time in a meeting that Sandy had
gone to him. George of course was the
director at the time and Sandy said,
"I've identified him. It's Aldrich
Ames." And it just so happened that
George had to attend a White House
briefing at which Ames was a
participant. And um
and George said that he just couldn't
look Ames in the eye. He knew he was a
traitor and he knew that he was going to
be arrested in just a couple of days.
And so he was determined only to look at
Ames's shoes so as not to give himself
away. And he said he couldn't help but
to see that the shoes were um
Oh, the shoes that that OJ Simpson wore,
those like $500 shoes. Do you remember
what those were?
>> Oh god. Um I don't remember what those
were. I had never heard of them at the
time. I had neither. They're like Prada
Prada shoes.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And then a couple of days
later, uh
>> that's always the thing, right? I mean,
these guys, these these moles
>> Yeah.
>> they have too much money. Um they're
living too high. That That's what it's
like the mob, right? That's what
attracts the wrong kind of attention.
>> Absolutely. I'm gonna I'm gonna Google
it real quickly. OJ Simpson's
shoes. And while you're doing that, let
me just bring in Robbie uh to talk about
>> Bruno Mali.
>> Bruno Mali. That's it. Well,
>> shoes.
>> Let me bring in producer Robbie. Uh
guys, we just have to ask you a quick
little favor and we're going to explain
this to you. Okay. Robbie's our
producer, Robbie West, who I'm going to
see next week in Montana. Um so, uh we
basically are trying to to get some
money here. And with the existing
audience that we have, if we can get
people to go over to Rumble and watch us
on Rumble, same exact experience,
there's a there's a live feed. It's
exactly the same thing. Um, instead of
YouTube, which pays not nearly as well.
Uh, John and I will have a little easier
time paying our bills every month.
>> You want to explain it?
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, for sure. Thank you all
for popping for popping me on. All
right. So, just real quick, I'm g try
and make this as precise and not boring
as possible. So, YouTube pays you based
off of ads. And basically, whenever you
click on a video, whenever an ad pops
up, they will literally throw a few
pennies to uh Ted and John here onto the
channel. What I'm working on doing is
getting deprogrammed into the Rumble
content creator program. And I want that
for a couple of different reasons. One,
Rumble is a free speech platform. So
what does that mean? It means that
Rumble will not one day decide that John
and Ted are being too controversial and
pull the plug. So if you like John and
Ted, go to Rumble and listen to them and
they'll be uncensored.
Second, Rumble pays you based off of
your watch hours. On YouTube, watch
hours mean nothing. So it's kind of like
TV or radio. So the more people that
watch, what happens is that they get
paid literally hundreds of dollars per
hour watched as opposed to maybe six or
seven dollars over on YouTube. And like
Ted was saying, the experience is
exactly the same with one big exception.
When you're on Rumble, if once you're in
the creator program, they have to do
five hours of Rumbleon only premium
content. So what does that mean? If
there's a topic that's particularly
controversial that y'all interested in
hearing,
then you can see it live on Rumble and
be able to continue supporting them and
be able to help them pay some bills. I
mean, y'all know what's going on with
them. Y'all know that that they lost
their income. So, while we ask y'all to
go over to Rumble, drop some follows. We
have thousands of people here watching
on YouTube. If only it
I'm I do not kid y'all. 20% of y'all do
what we're asking. It would make a
radical change financially
for Ted and for John. That's all I got
for you. Now, drop the link in the chat.
>> Okay. Uh the chat that it's it's in
here. It's rumble rumble.com
inexplicably
dprogram show, but you can just go to
Rumble and just search for Dprogram and
Ted Roller or John Kuryaku and you will
find it. Robbie, thank you so much for
that. Um okay, sorry for the ad guys. I
mean, it's like we're getting to be like
NPR John. Anyway, you were saying about
Sarah about Sandy Grimes.
>> Yeah. So, here she catches one of the
most prolific uh moles in modern
American history. And then the next day,
she came into work and just went about
her normal job looking for the next
mole.
So, I felt bad when I saw she died. I
didn't realize that she was 80 years
old, but God bless her. She was really
one of those unknown heroes, those
unsung heroes at the CIA. You know,
every once in a while the CIA will give
out something called a trailblazer
award. I never understood these things.
And most of them will be, you know,
white men who were station chief like,
you know, in Havana when the when
Batista was overthrown or station chief
when the last guy was pulled out of
South Vietnam on the helicopter. And
then they'll they'll toss one to
somebody like Bonnie Hersburg. I worked
for Bonnie uh in the office of
leadership analysis. Bonnie was a
terrific analyst. She was an okay
manager.
What she what trail she blazed, I will
never ever ever understand because she
was just kind of a typical
run-of-the-mill manager. But then you
have people like like this who um you
know are unsung.
But anyway, that's the CIA today. Lot of
news coming in the CIA today. What what
is what is before we move on from from
her I mean what is the what are the
personality traits that are required to
catch a mole like what skill set is
required I mean it's not you have to
navigate also you're you're in the case
of an Aldridge Ames you're you're
bringing down someone who's uh you know
got title uh position above your own
>> oh yes you have a lot of institutional
resistance no one wants to hear it right
>> no one wants to hear it and I'll tell
you But there are no bigger secrets than
the counter intelligence center at the
CIA. Um,
that's a very important question you've
asked, Ted. The the mole hunter at the
CIA has to be somebody who is obsessed
with secrecy
to the point where you don't even talk
to yourself like in your own head. Like
for me, I'd be I'd go to the credit
union and say, "I'm taking you down,
Ames. you bastard. I would never fit in
in a position like that.
>> Um,
>> and you have to and you and you have to
not really care about like people
telling you, "Shut up, Kiryaku." Like,
you're you're you just don't like that
you don't like games because you don't
like his politics. You don't like the
cut of his jib. This is personal. You're
going after a good patriot, someone
who's doing God's work for America, and
you're being an [__]
>> That's right. That's right. U and and
listen, somebody in counter intelligence
is akin to somebody in internal affairs
in a police department.
>> I'll give you another example.
>> No one likes you.
>> I I'll give you an example. On my uh on
my first at the end of my first full
week at the agency, my boss walked me
around both the new headquarters
building and the old headquarters
building just to point out where
everything was. Right. Here's the
cafeteria. Here's the credit union.
There's medical services. This in the
lobby of the new building is it's it's
all glass like a glass atrium and they
have windows and one window says health
insurance and one window says life
insurance and one window says sports
tickets, right? And then there were a
couple of other windows. He said this is
where you go if you want to buy baseball
tickets, basketball, hockey, football
tickets, right? And then there was
another one that said,
well, I shouldn't say what it said, but
it was the window that you go to if
maybe you have a little bit of a
drinking problem
>> or you've got a problem with your credit
or maybe you're taking care of your
elderly parents and it's too much of a
burden. He told me, "Don't ever go to
that window." I said, "Why? It's nice
that they do things like that."
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And he said, "Because
the people at that window work for
counterintelligence
and they don't give a [__] about your
elderly parents. They want to know if
you're in a bad enough spot that you're
going to turn mole."
So this is so this is a little bit like
uh in the cultural revolution
let a thousand flowers bloom
>> where the Chinese Communist Party and
said oh we're opening up to ourselves to
criticism you know all you academics all
you people who might be accused of being
counterrevolutionaries
step forward the party's a big tent we
want to hear from all of you guys then
you step forward
>> off to a May 4th farm
>> nobody ever sees you again.
>> Yeah,
>> that's right.
>> Wow. That is I mean that's some dark
cynical [__]
>> That was my first week. I'm like, "Holy
shit." I never even went in there to to
buy a a ticket to the ball game. I was
just afraid of somebody just seeing me
go in there.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, you can. That That's what
Tickatron is for. Um or mouse or
whatever the [__] it's called now.
>> That's exactly right.
>> Oh, man. That is that is so so dark. Um
>> All right. Should we uh should we talk
about um Palestine? I mean uh we have
>> you were right, Ted. You were right
about Kirst. And frankly, I didn't think
he had the guts to do it. But then he
kind of made a half step if you don't
mind my you know taking over the
conversation.
>> Please.
>> He said we're going to we're going to
recognize Palestine in September unless
the Israelis let food in and are nicer
people about it.
>> It's a decision to sign by committee,
right? You can tell that and um you know
and but I think it's probably very easy
to agree to. I mean it's it's kind of
like well okay fine. I mean the Israelis
are not going to do this. I mean, it
does have kind of I mean, I don't like
it either because I feel one of the
commenters uh deep down in the thread
pointed out that really uh this
recognition should just be based on uh
not as a reward, a punishment for
Israel, but it should just be a
statement of self-determination for the
Palestinian people. Couldn't agree more.
In the original documents that led to
the creation of Israel, and there's even
a YouTube video of of Harry Truman
talking about this,
it says that Israel is going to be
created, you know, today, whatever 1948,
and Palestine will be created as an
independent state pending further
discussion. Okay, that was 1948
and we're still talking about it. Now
that said, we are there's 153 nations. I
guess it's going to be 155 soon. Um,
Australia is apparently uh cir is uh
getting ready to go to shoot to to pull
the trigger. Um, Luxembourg is getting
ready to pull the trigger.
>> I didn't see that one.
>> And uh and and there's there's a whole
pel of other European countries that are
Croatia.
>> Yes. Croatia. Spain.
>> Yeah. Spain's already in.
>> Well, they're already in.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, I mean, I think
basically, uh, it's like you said, it's
going to be just the Axis powers of
Germany and and and Japan and Italy who
are going to be out with the US. What a
what a what a mly crew. And, um, you
know, but but so, yeah. No, it's it's a
big deal. I mean, I think the the
pressure built so fast on Starmer.
That's what I I mean, I knew it was
going to happen. I just didn't think it
would happen this quickly. And you know
what started it was these pictures that
ran in the BBC of starving children that
just opened the floodgates.
>> I I really believe that.
>> Yeah. Well, let's talk about that.
Someone brought it up and I apologize
because this was further and down, but
I'm glad that someone uh asked about
this question. So, um there was this
very one particular photo of this one
kid who was really, really, really sick
and with these haunting eyes. And you
can see why the why this particular
photo went viral. And um the New York
Times and other corporate media
organizations have walked that back
obviously in response to Zionists who've
complained that the kid aside from
suffering from starvation also had other
diseases at the same time. Right? So
therefore, but those other So the
implication being maybe that these other
diseases are wasting diseases, but
they're not. Um but the kids was really
really sick and he's starving. So um and
he's that's which is why he was at the
hospital. But um you know, look to me
it's kind of like well what do you you
know what do we make of that? My answer
to that is I think it's the you know
it's the last gasp of a dying regime. I
mean, I think Israel is in real trouble
now.
>> I I agree. I agree. And I don't think
that they really realize just how deep
they are. I saw an interview, well,
maybe you saw it, too. It's it's Tucker
Carlson's latest interview. Uh, it just
dropped and it's with John Mirshimer,
who is absolutely freaking brilliant.
And Mirshimer
essentially said that he said that the
Israelis just don't realize how how deep
they're in. And and on the contrary,
they're talking about
this concept of a greater Israel, which
is like includes the bottom third of
Lebanon, the southern third of Lebanon.
It includes, you know, another 50 miles
inside of uh of Syria. It includes the
entire West Bank and it includes the
Gaza, I'm sorry, the the Sinai
Peninsula. It's like, wait a minute, you
guys should be thinking about your
survival here and about your country
falling apart because you're carrying
out a genocide
and you've got people who are in
government talking about greater Israel.
Mir Shimemer made another important
point
and this is how unhinged the American
evangelical Christian community is where
you've got the likes of Ambassador
Huckabe or Speaker of the House Mike
Johnson
>> Mhm.
>> saying that Jesus wants us to support
Israel and Israel's policy. Well, last
week Israel's policy was to utterly and
completely destroy one of the last
surviving Christian villages in the West
Bank, drive out all the Christians and
steal their land. So, you're saying
Jesus wants wants the Jews to drive out
the Christians,
>> and that's what we're going with.
>> It makes absolutely no sense at all. And
so many Americans don't know how many
Christians there are in Palestine. A lot
of them. Um the by the way though%
>> I do want to say and one of the things
you wanted to talk about was uh the you
know the the the split now the growing
split on the American right over Israel.
And I do want to be fair to Ambassador
Huckabe. He's the US ambassador to
Israel. He went to the West Bank and
visited that town that's been repeatedly
attacked by violent fascist settlers.
Probably most of whom are from like my
neighbors from Brooklyn. Right.
>> They're from New Jersey and New York.
>> Yeah. and those and those those those
scumbags who've been uh you know mur
murder murdering, raping and pillaging
over there. Uh but at least he went
there and he was he expressed concern
and he was I think turned off by what
the the settlers were doing. He showed
up. Um Joe Rogan, who I think is
unfairly characterized as a
right-winger, but he's boycotting
apparently he's not allowing BB
Netanyahu to come on a show he who BB
wants to come on. Um, you know, I mean,
I I think they're losing the thread, the
Israelis. Um, I mean, I mean, we're
talking about a country that is
uniquely, right, it's unique, right?
It's the only country that's currently
on the face of the planet that owes its
existence to the United Nations. It's
the only complete welfare state that
owes its entire ex economy to the United
States of America. It's ignoring the UN
and its resolutions. It's ignoring
public opinion in the US, the tax among
the taxpayers who are paying that bill
to the Israelis. I mean, these people
are biting, chomping, stabbing, and
hacking at the hand that feeds them.
>> And you know, I mean, they're a rabid
dog. And you know, I mean, I I I wrote a
column this week that's called that
Israel no longer has the right to exist.
And
>> yeah, I read that
>> and thank you. the the argument that you
know I'm trying to make here is in the
community of nations there are some
things you just can't that people can't
tolerate like you know when Napoleon
disrupted Europe um all these disperate
powers who had competing interests got
together to defeat him even though they
hated each other you know World War II
uh you know the US and the USSR were not
buds but they had to come together to
fight Nazi Germany not to stop the
Holocaust because I mean the US
certainly didn't care about about it. I
mean, certainly the Russians cared more
about it because it happened on their
ter in their territory. But the, you
know, they came in and they got together
because Nazi Germany was so militarily
aggressive and violent and out of
control and disruptive, they just had to
be put down like a rabid dog. I mean,
same and imperial Japan the same way.
That's exactly the scenario that we have
now with Israel. They're such a
destabilizing force in the Middle East,
right? I mean, literally, even if you
count like Iran, you know, and the Axis
of resistance and all the shenanigans
they had going on with the Houthis and
all that.
>> Yeah.
>> It's nothing compared to Israel, right?
I mean, just in the last few months,
right? They bombed Iran. They did they
overthrew the government of Syria and
now they're bombing the new government
that they installed.
>> Yes.
>> I mean, these people are nuts.
>> They are nuts. And you know, I have to
say, uh, where did I just see it? It was
uh
well, thank you everybody first of all
for for going on to uh there it is. What
what nonsense says USA sex predators
flee to Israel. Oh boy are you right. So
listen to this. I was in prison with a a
pedophile. This disgusting horrible
pedophile.
He had graduated from Harvard and
Harvard Law School and he was an
attorney in Moscow.
Um he
to make a very long story very short he
um was a an aficionado of the ballet and
so he offered to pay the tuition for a
12-year-old Russian boy but he insisted
that the boy live with him. The parents
were like, "I don't know about that."
But they were poor and this kid was like
a once- in a generation gifted ballet
guy. And so they allowed their
12-year-old to move in with a guy, um,
Ken.
Kenneth. So, uh,
12 hours later, Ken was raping this kid.
And this went on for five years.
Finally,
um, the kid told the FBI what was
happening. They issued an arrest
warrant. By then, Ken was back in
Philadelphia where his parents were
exceedingly wealthy, big humanitarians.
They, you know, donate to the museum,
whatever. He ran immediately to Israel
and the Israelis would not extradite him
because they
>> would not the Israelis don't extradite
Jews.
>> It's a it's a it's a law in Israel. They
don't care what he's accused of. They're
not extraditing any Jew.
So, we asked for the extradition. They
said no.
Um,
and then
Interpol came up with an idea that was
absolutely genius. I love when I hear
about these these brilliant operational
ideas that people come up with. This was
my favorite thing to do at the CIA was
just to sit around thinking up ideas
with with my colleagues.
They decided
to
they decided to sponsor a ballet show in
Cyprus
and they used a dummy email account to
email him an announcement of the ballet
>> to lure him
>> and they lured him to Cyprus and they
grabbed him at the airport and the
criates extradited him and he got 20
years. He's still in that bastard.
>> But the Israelis will not extradite
Jews. Period.
>> That's pretty gross. I mean, I just
Yeah. I mean, I I think Look, I think
the I think we're we're done here. So,
look, what's what do you think is going
to happen? I mean, by the Okay, so
September now feels really far away.
>> It does. I agree. And it's not it's four
and a half, five weeks,
>> right? So the so the UN so it's going to
be Labor Day.
>> The UN's going to come here to New York
and [__] up all the traffic and no one's
gonna be able to move.
>> And in that traffic is going to be a lot
of new allies of or at least friends of
Palestine.
>> Um how many countries do you think it's
going to be? It's going to be like the m
our migration over to Rumble. Everyone
subscribing over there. Um you know
Palestine's signing them up. Um
>> oh and by the way I I did want to ask
you a little bit about this statement
that broke. I don't know if you had a
chance to hear it because it just
happened right before we went on the
air, but uh Arab and Muslim states u a
member of the Arab League, the EU and 17
more countries have supported a
declaration signed at a UN conference
that was hosted by Saudi Arabia and
France that basically uh is calling this
also includes this cutter Saudi and Saud
Saudis and Egypt. They're calling for
Hamas to disarm and give up power and
basically turn over all authority to the
Palestinian Authority, which of course
is Makbas, who's what, 92 or something
like that.
>> Yeah. I always say he's he's 16 years
into a four-year term.
>> Nice. He and he and Zalinsky have a nice
democracy they they're working on.
That's right. And and anyway, so they
Yeah, he's over there. Um, so Makmoud
Abbas, the sort of the the head of the I
I guess it's like the Vichi kind of
government of the West Bank kind of
>> corrupt.
>> Yeah, they're corrupt and they don't
really do anything. But basically,
that's what all these countries are
calling for. Like they don't want to
recognize Hamas.
>> I mean
I mean that's not it's not going to
happen, right? I mean because first of
all that's fat and they can't rule in
Gaza. The Gazins don't want them.
>> No. No. The Gazins have made it clear by
voting Hamas in and the PA out. The PA
is not the answer to this problem. you
know, Harets two or three weeks ago ran
this article saying that one of the
things that's being discussed, and I
think it isn't actually being discussed,
I think they just put it out there to
see what the reaction was going to be,
um, was to have Hamas disarm and then to
have Saudi Arabia administer Gaza while
Israel continues to actually own Gaza.
And then after a day, nobody really
commented on it. And can I say something
too about Cypress? This this thing that
that the uh Israelis said about northern
Cypress being an Israel problem. Um they
they mean something actually
contemporary on that. The Greeks, I am
utterly ashamed to say that the Greeks
and the Criates are 1,000% pro-Israel.
And the reason that they're pro- Israel
is severalfold. Number one, it's because
um it's because the
Israelis and the Turks hate each other.
So if the Turks hate Israel, then the
Greeks have to love Israel because the
Greeks hate
>> the enemy of my enemy is my friend.
>> There it is. The other reason is because
>> the Criates are sitting on an ocean of
natural gas and it stretches into
Israeli waters. And so the Greeks, the
Cypri
>> and and into Palestinian waters, right?
>> Gazin waters.
>> Gazin waters. Yes. And just like one
little vein into Lebanese waters.
>> Mhm. So the Greeks and Criates don't
have the money to uh to lift this gas,
but the Israelis certainly do. And so
the three countries have entered into
this joint venture that's already well
underway to lift this gas. and it's
going to make Cypress one of the
wealthiest countries in the in the in
the world over the course of years. So,
we just I'm not going to say celebrated,
I'm going to say commemorated
>> the 51st anniversary of the Turkish
invasion of Cypress.
>> Oh, wow.
>> The Turks invaded Cypress, killed
thousands of Criates. 17 American
citizens are still missing from the
Turkish invasion 51 years ago.
>> Yeah. This was in the 70s. Yeah.
>> 1974.
>> Yeah.
>> And um
>> I never understood what was the what was
the
>> what was Turkey after. I mean besides
just territory.
>> There were a lot of moving parts in this
thing. So these were were literally the
final days of the Greek military
dictatorship. And as it was in its death
throws, it overthrew the democratically
elected government of Cyprus and
installed a strong man by the name of
Nikos Samson, who had been an assassin
in sort of his previous life. So Samson
announced a military dictatorship in
Cyprus. The Turks saw that as the green
light to invade and overthrow Samson,
which they did in a matter of days.
So the the democratically elected
president returns to Cyprus. He'd only
been in exile a week and the Turks never
left and they've just kept onethird of
Cypress, the northern third of Cypress.
So what we're seeing here um what we're
seeing here with the Israelis saying we
have a problem with northern Cypress.
There is no such thing as northern
Cypress with a capital N. Um, the Turks
call it the the trunk, the Turkish
Republic of Northern Cypress. It's not
recognized by any country in the world
except Turkey,
>> right? It's Turkey. It's Turkish
annexed. It's Turkish annexed or Turkish
occupied Cypress is what it is.
>> It's just occupied Cyprus. Yeah. And so
because the Israelis and the Greeks and
the Criates are all in business
together, the the Greeks and the Criates
went to the Israelis and says, "Hey,"
they say, "Hey, we we need your help on
on Cyprus. You need to say the right
thing about the Turks." And so the
Israelis hate the Turks like the Turks
hate the Israelis. So they jump in on
the side of the Greeks and the Criates.
It's awful.
>> Let's ask Let's I do want to answer this
question uh by Godna.
>> Yeah.
>> Why would anyone Sorry, not that too.
Um, is I'm have Okay, we'll answer this
one. Why would anyone trust Saudi Arabia
to administer Gaza? Um, they wouldn't
>> is the short answer.
>> They wouldn't. I wouldn't.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, they're not.
>> And then and then also um Yeah, that the
scroll is moving so fast I'm having a
hard Oh, here we go. Um, can you find
your can you can we explain what what
what happens as uh you know with
countries recognizing Palestine?
>> It's really I mean it's so it is
symbolic. it doesn't change the facts on
the ground and there is the concern that
um you know in the case of of the
republic of pal the future republic of
Palestine or the present republic of
Palestine depending on how you want to
look at it it's divided right I mean
it's literally um there's two
governments there's the Hamas government
and there's the Palestinian Authority um
that's kind of an issue because you're
supposed to know who you'd be able to
talk to u but you know I guess like
that's not being but I mean it what
happens is it's legitimate right So the
big thing is if you're a country that
has a deal with Israel or is thinking of
making a deal with Israel, once you
recognize Palestine, you have to go
through all of your trading agreements
and everything that you have with Israel
to see if anything in there is wrong or
illegal or challenging to Palestine. So
a good example of that would be let's
say so Israel produces wine. They
produce it in uh occupied territories
for example in the
Heights. Yeah. Which is, by the way, I
have to admit, I've had uh this treason
wine. It's it's really good.
>> Yeah. It's really good. So, the Golan
the Golan wine is um you know, for
example, you would not if you've
recognized Syria as an independent
country, which most of the world does.
Well, you can't import that wine into
your country. And it's just a million
little things like that and they add up.
I mean, and there's more to it than
that, too, right? If there's a genocide
taking place, um, in your country, uh,
in in you're recognized by another
country, you can call their ambassador
and say, "Listen, I need your help. Um,
you know, there's stuff that we we need
we need your cooperation. Can you help
help us with intel? Can you you know,
there's can you can you stop deregnize
Israel? There's lots of stuff like
suddenly the doors are open. You're not
isolated." Um it reminds me a little bit
of a strange uh meeting I had with the
Afghan ambassador to uh Usuzbekistan
during the Taliban period in and this
was like in 2000 it was in 2000. So it
was the first
>> was he Talib?
>> So he was a he was a northern alliance
guy.
So I'm so he had the embassy in Tashkant
and um and so I so I asked him like well
you know technically you're supposed to
be getting support from the US and he
said oh yeah he goes um we're supposed
to be and I said what kind of support do
you get and he opens up his desk drawer
pulls out a yellow envelope and he's
like here you go. I open it up and
inside there's a map of Afghanistan
and I'm like it's just and he goes
that's the only support I have ever
gotten from the US government. Like
that's it. And I go well it's a it's a
pretty good map. He goes it's out of
date. He said the Soviet ones are
better.
>> And he's like and uh and I was like so
how do you pay for all this? And he was
like hemming and hawing. And I was like
you guys mine rubies. And he's like,
"Yeah, in Badakshan."
So that's, you know, that's how they
were subsisting. But yeah, but I mean,
so I don't know. I mean, what do you
think is I mean, what does it what's the
practical meaning of of recognition for
the Palestinians?
>> I think um it opens the door for
Palestine to be a member state in a lot
of different international
organizations, which gives them a voice
on the international stage that they
otherwise wouldn't have had. uh it makes
them eligible for uh for financial aid
both from international organizations
and from uh individual countries.
And uh you know
we used to have a Palestine liaison
office here in in Washington. Uh Donald
Trump closed it in his first term and
expelled the Palestinian diplomats. Uh,
I would love to see Palestinian
diplomats on the circuit again in
Washington or in London or Madrid or,
you know, Canberra or anywhere else
where they're recognized
>> and they could be and they could
eventually have like one of those
rotating seats at the Security Council
um at at the UN.
>> Exactly right. Exactly right. So they
would be they would be the
representative of the Asia group on the
UN Security Council. Oh my god. Could
you imagine?
>> Huge.
>> Huge. Absolutely huge. When I was at the
CIA, it was Libya's turn. And we went
apeshit over the notion that Muamar
Gaddafi would be represented on the
United Nations uh security council. And
so we started this international
lobbying effort and we got the Asia
group to to deny
seeding Libya on the security council
and Egypt got it two terms in a row.
>> Ridiculous.
>> There were no other countries in all of
Asia,
you know, that should have been
represented on the UN Security Council.
>> Right. Right. By the way, uh really uh I
think good point here from Sky. Uh after
September, the US will be the only
permanent member of the security council
not to recognize Palestinian statethood.
>> That is a very good point.
>> That's a very thing is Israel is going
to be a pariah. The question for
President Trump and for the United
States and really frankly Trump, we
shouldn't pick on him on this because
Democrats are equally guilty for having
supported Israel.
>> Absolutely. And this whole genocide
started under Biden and he encouraged it
and he funded it and he armed it. So,
uh, you know, Trump just happens to be
holding the bag right now. But the
question for the US is going to be, do
we want to be at the pariah table with
little Israel or do we want to be with
everyone else?
>> Well, you know, in these in these votes
in the UN General Assembly, it's it's
not just us in Israel. It's also Naru
and occasionally Costa Rica and uh you
know one of those little countries in
the Pacific that I can't pronounce. So
we're not always standing alone, right?
>> Like Vanuatu.
>> Vanuatu.
Where would we be without Vanuatu?
>> Well, Vanuatu, I think Vanuatu is the uh
closest to the international date line.
So on New Year's Eve, they always are
like, "Well, Vanuatu celebrated 23 and a
half hours ago.
You've seen that?
>> Unbelievable. Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's It's I'll answer I'll answer
Yellow Banana's question. I'll be in New
York City Labor Day weekend. How bad
will traffic be for the UN?
>> Horrible. Espec if you're staying on the
up on the east side.
>> East side.
>> The east side is in Manhattan is is
terrible. If you're like somewhere else,
honestly, if you're up like I'm on the
upper west.
>> I had a I had a UN badge and I had
trouble getting to the office.
even with a UN badge and and I was
walking so it's going to be bad on the
east side. Stay away from the east side.
>> Yeah. And it's always it's it's kind of
like in general that's that's good
advice anyway. Um Labor Day but all the
rich people will be gone so in other
neighborhoods it'll kind of help. It's
kind of like a great time to visit town.
Um
>> uh and the weather should be a little
bit better. Um oh my god. So all right.
What do we think of Kaddafi? I love that
question. And I I I I think Gaddafi was
super I mean no one got screwed more
than Gaddafi, right? I mean and and what
happened to him is so is so important as
a you know lesson for other rulers,
right? I mean George W. Bush said,
"Listen, you know, if you drop your
nuclear program, uh and you know, we'll
cut a deal with you. We'll bring you in.
Um we'll legitimize you. We'll forget
all about Locker B, the whole nine
yards." And then he did as asked and the
next thing you know uh Hillary Clinton
comes in as secretary of state. There's
this uh radical jihadi movement out in
eastern Libya in in Benghazi and the US
finances it runs interference for it
provides air support with NATO and we
helped kill Gaddafi and get him
sodomized on on
>> live my boss Steve Kappus
deputy director the associate deputy
director for operations and and a mentor
of mine flew out to Libya to meet with
Gaddafi and uh Gaddafi's intelligence
chief who actually graduated from the
University of Michigan um and uh and
convinced him to give up his weapons of
mass destruction programs saying you
don't want to end up like Saddam
Hussein. We're going to kill Saddam
Hussein. He told Gaddafi in two in 2002.
We're going to kill him.
>> You don't want to end that.
>> Just give up your weapons of mass
destruction and everybody's going to
live happily ever after. And Gaddafi
gave up all his weapons programs.
>> A rube.
>> And we allowed him to be killed anyway.
>> And he got played.
>> Yeah, he got played. We just lied to
him. And then, you know, the way he was
killed was so horrific. It was so
grotesque.
>> And people think that's just the local.
They think that's the locals who did it,
but that's not true. I mean, it was a US
uh drone that fired a missile at his
motorcade and maybe at his car
specifically, but his car was driven off
the road. He and his entourage forced to
flee. They hid in a in a drainage pipe
culvert kind of thing. Yes. And then
then the uh the giadis found him and and
killed him.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh so yeah, let's talk a little bit
about do we want to talk about this? I
do. I mean, it's what's so remarkable
about the mass shooting that took place
at 345 Park Avenue here and 51st Street
is that it's not remarkable. Um, you
know, this guy came in, he claimed in
reminded me of the um the the shooter at
the University of Texas in Austin in
1966, the Texas Watchtower shooter. Um,
he suspected there was something wrong
with him, that he was hearing voices and
having violent urges. And in his suicide
note, he he asked he requested that his
brain be examined for uh signs of
trouble. And in fact, they did find a
tumor that was pressing up against his
amydala. And uh that's so and so this
guy yesterday um he his suicide note
said that he believed he had CTE. I
don't know if he had ever been diagnosed
formally or not. He was a high school
football player. He went to the NFL
building HQ uh and basically went to the
wrong floor, killed four people,
including an offduty New York City
police officer who was working security
at the desk. And um you know, the thing
is though, it's one of those things
where if you say, "Well, what could you
possibly do about it?" I mean, I think
nothing. I mean, you know, it's like
people guns are legal, AR-15s are legal,
there's they're we're washing them.
They're all over the place. um you know,
he drove here from Nevada. Uh he parked
in front of the building in his BMW and
walked in. I mean, this can and will
happen over and over again. And it's
almost like all you can do is just
shrug. And I think that's the part
that's what's so remarkable about it is
how unremarkable it is.
>> And you know, he he apologized in the
note that he left, which just to me made
it that much more sad. Yeah,
>> mental illness, whether it's caused by
CTE or or something else, is is a
horrible existence.
>> And he really believed that he had CTE
and he really believed that it was
because he uh played football in high
school.
>> Yeah. So he was
>> Yeah. So it seems to be like kind of
it's a political act basically.
>> Yeah. Right. It is. Yes, it is. It's a
political act.
>> John, should we talk about Yeah. Should
we talk about this uh story out of Iran?
So, obviously, the Iranians are still
smarting from the uh their 12-day 14-day
war with uh I guess 12-day war with uh
Israel. And um they're licking their
wounds, but their their whatever their
nuclear program was appears to be
largely intact. But the Iranians took
note and they're starting to think and
they obviously are investigating what
happened. And part of their
investigation finds that um their GPS
was manipulated by the US or Israel
andor Israel andor other some kind of
other bad actor uh to screw up their
targeting abilities. This might help
explain why they were so uh caught with
their pants down and unable to defend
themselves uh and fire back against the
Israelis who had complete uh you know
command of the skies over Iran which to
me blew my blew me away.
>> This has been a rumor really since since
the 12-day war that something was wrong
with the GPS's. You're not allowed to
use ways in Iran because ways is owned
by an Israeli company. But yes, NEGPS,
the Iranian,
>> right? Ways was purchased by Google.
It's now part of Alphabet. Yeah,
>> correct. Um, it was founded by an
Israeli company.
>> That's right.
>> So, uh,
>> I always hated it. I never understood
it. I didn't understand like how it like
the interface makes no sense to me.
Maybe, maybe you have to read from right
to left or something.
>> Maybe.
But I think it's they're worried about
GPS's in general now just because they
believe probably rightly that the US and
Israel have the technology to be able to
um interface with the satellites
>> and target Iran.
>> Well, there are satellites, right? I
mean,
>> Bill Clinton, right? This was this was
military and covert technology, right?
Until Bill Clinton decided to publicize
it. Um, I think wisely he was convinced
that this was going to open up all sorts
of technological innovation and it it
has. I mean, if you think about
something like, you know, you look at
real estate listings and, you know, you
can see a map of where the house is or
whatever, it's it's amazing. But that
technology, it's American and and it can
be it can and was weaponized against the
Iranians. So now they're looking for a
Chinese or other alternative. Um, this
story is not about Iran. This story is
about the US having technological
dominance.
>> That's right.
>> And and then that dominance being
undermined by the US's willingness to
weaponize that dominance um for
short-term gain, losing sight of the
long-term impact, which is that if you
come off as a non-neutral arbiter, uh
you know, you're not the rest of the
world isn't going to want to trust you
anymore, and then you're going to lose
your advantage. I mean, you know, we
invented the phone. That's why our area
that's why our country code is one um
you know we we we have I mean this is
exact it's analogous to the dollar right
we weaponized the US dollar so now
Russia everyone else who's thinking well
one day I could fall a foul of I mean
Belgium you could fall a foul of the
United States you don't know and then
you know they could just decide to turn
off the spigot and screw us and steal
our for our reserve currency like we
can't have that so you know get, you
know, Swift or all these bank all these
systems that if you want to control them
and and take a little piece, you can't
like put your thumb on the I mean the
example I'm thinking of is like, you
know, how did Constantinople become
rich, right? Well, it's like right on
the Bosphorus and they just collected
tolls, right, from the Silk Road and
just waited for ships to go through and
everybody had to pay. And what made it
work was they let everyone through and
they charged everyone. If they had
started to say like, ah, you know, the
the [__] those Sagdians, let's nail
them. Um, then like that wouldn't have
worked. Other people would have been
like, well, we have to overthrow the the
the Constantinople or we have to do an
end route. We have to figure another
way.
>> Yeah.
>> The US just doesn't I don't know. It
seems really really shortsighted.
>> Very very shortsighted. And we had the
same conversation last week about
sanctions. Countries have gotten to the
point where sanctions just simply don't
hurt them anymore because we are so
heavy in the way we we levy sanctions
against countries that they're forced to
come up with the way around them. And
let me interrupt uh our conversation for
one second. Uh just as we were going on
the air, exactly 60 60 minutes ago,
Prime Minister um Mark Carney, the
Canadian Prime Minister, announced that
Canada would recognize Palestine.
>> Holy [__]
That's amazing.
I just had a little tingle there in my
in my upper back. That's so great.
>> It's it's happening. You're right. It's
there's a hole in the dyke.
>> The flood
>> and it's it's it's coming. It's s it's
you know to take a story from uh from
the from from northeastern Russia it's
it's a seismic shift. It's a tsunami.
I mean but it is I mean no it is
>> and Canada is also I mean diplomatically
a very important country. I mean, you
know, very much Canada is the country
that when you're a backpacker and you
want to travel to like you're an
American backpacker and you want to go
to like Afghanistan and not be thought
of as an [__] you wear the you put
that Canadian flag on your backpack,
right? Canada's considered neutral.
>> I did that. I sewed a Canadian flag on
my backpack in the summer of 85.
>> Everyone thinks Canada is is chill. Um
I'm wondering what can Canada cander
strike means here. Canada is following
orders from whom, I wonder.
>> No, that that doesn't make sense to me.
>> Yeah. Well, you can pipe in uh we'll
we'll put that up whatever you if you
reply to us. Um but yeah, so yeah,
exactly. Houdini is like always say
you're Canadian overseas like oh like
yeah I like hockey. Um
but yeah, so we'll we'll see what
happens here. Um,
oh, so, uh, yeah. So, there's so much
cynical cynicism here, right? I'm not
buying it. These elites that back to
genocide already can't do good.
>> Um, look, it's not because they're good
people. It's because they read polls and
like they know that basically the world
isn't this. I mean, if they were good
people, they would have come out against
this [__] on October 8th, 2023. I mean,
you know, this is like because it was
already obvious what the what the
Israelis were going to do from within
hours. I mean, they were they were
having a great time. You know, they were
looking forward to it.
>> Yeah.
>> So, um
>> you know, I wonder if some of this is a
swipe at Donald Trump, too, from from
the Canadians.
>> I wonder.
>> It could be. It could be. Well, they
have reason to be pissed,
>> right?
Right.
>> Um I think Yeah. I mean, I don't know.
I'm not ruling out that Donald Trump is
going to distance himself from Israel. I
don't It's not like he's going to like
recognize Palestine, but he's right.
>> I think the weapons flow has to come to
an end.
>> It does. Alyssa Slotkin, some a couple
people have mentioned Alyssa Slotkin in
the uh in the uh chat. She's the senator
from uh Michigan, former CIA colleague
of mine. Uh
she,
you know, Alyssa's complicated. She's
Jewish. She was not endorsed by any of
the Jewish groups in America uh in her
campaign. U but she won. She won
relatively easily in a in a year when
Donald Trump carried her state. Um but
she said that she would be willing to
vote for a cut off of offensive weapons
uh to to Israel. That's not going to
happen.
>> We saw a week ago there was a vote to
cut off offensive weapons to Israel and
it got like six votes in the House. So
it's just not going to it's not going to
happen.
Well, I I don't think it's going to
happen quickly, but I think I think by
by Christmas time, I think we're going
to see we're going to see some movement
or it's gonna it's going to slow down or
something. Do you do you think do you
think that if it keeps happening if if
country after country you know not
including of course Hungary, Italy,
Germany, the United States, but if these
other countries continue to recognize
Palestine,
do you think that this could threaten
the Netanyahu government?
>> Yeah. Um
>> because somebody's going to have to take
the blame for losing the international
community,
>> right? And that has to be that has to be
BB, right? I mean, um I I did a deep
dive into Israeli opinion polling, as
you know, because you read my column. Um
yeah, and 76.5%
of Israelis as of June
>> um totally have no problem with the
genocide. They're like a okay with it.
And they don't think that Palestinian uh
that the the needs of the Palestinians
and their misery should even be taken
into consideration in military planning.
Right. So, this is um you know, let's
let's be clear here. Even what passes
for the Israeli left, they're not
demonstrating against the genocide.
They're demonstrating because the
hostages haven't come home. Yeah. And
and also they don't like Netanyahu um
and and his corruption. But that's what
this is about, right? Um, so we looking
at it from the It's hard for me to see
this from the point standpoint of the
Israelis who basically have their heads
up their asses while the whole rest of
the world is appalled and disgusted with
them and they don't see it. But I do
think if from their point of view, if
they're involved in an existential
battle to expand Israel, drive and get
Gaza for themselves, um, which obviously
all is Israelis aren't stupid. They know
that's what this is about.
and that that project is going to be
deeply hampered by losing US and
international support.
Yeah. Yeah. Who else are you going to
blame? I mean, you can't alard it. Say,
well, this is Ben Gir, but not, you
know, but not Netanyahu. It's like it's
all of them. The government's got to go.
>> I mean, it's not like we're going to
they're not going to be replaced with
liberals, but
>> No. No. There aren't any anymore in
Israel.
>> No.
>> No. If there's a ceasefire, does BB go
to prison? Well, if BB If BB is out of
government,
>> if he's out of government,
>> BB goes to trial.
>> Yes.
>> And then probably he goes to prison, I
think.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. And this is a good point. Oh,
thank you, Can Candace Strike. Thank you
very much. Um
uh where did I just see it? It we're
we're getting so many comments I can't
keep up. Yeah. Um, pug droid mixdeen
don't think they can admit wrongdoing on
anything. It's a mountain of war crimes.
That's exactly right.
>> Yeah. Well, that's for sure.
>> And and and that's why that's why
Netanyahu can't risk not being prime
minister.
>> Here's a big question for you. You know,
back in the old days, people like Edamin
would go into exile in places like Saudi
Arabia.
>> That's right. I saw him in Jedha in the
in the vegetable market.
>> What? I was like, "Oh my god, that's
Ediam." And he was there with his wife
like
>> shopping for ears.
>> Seriously? Right. What a monster.
>> You know, there's a there's a famous
story uh I forget if it was Time or
Newsweek, but one of them interviewed
him and uh at and on the back porch of
his presidential palace and uh at and he
um at one point uh was presented with a
plate of human ears with tomato garnish
and said like, "This is a delicacy in
our country. Would you like one?"
>> Oh my god. I remember reading an article
once saying that in a conversation with
a reporter he he was talking about the
saltiness of bush meat and he said
monkeys are salty, leopards are very
salty but nothing is as salty as a human
being.
>> Yeah, he was a famous cannibal. Um did
you ever see the that movie with the f
by the French brothers? Um the it's in
the criterion collection. It's just
called Idia mean dada.
It's one of the it's one of the most
amazing film. It's a documentary. So
this is amazing film, right? So
basically
>> for six months these two French brothers
were given unfettered access to Ediamin.
They followed him everywhere. Um they
and this was right after uh the antbi uh
mission by the Israelis and oddly
>> his brother was killed
>> and and and it had changed him
apparently
Ediamin um like for the filmmakers had
the his army recreate the antbi mission
from and they brings out helicopters and
[__] You got to watch it. It's like
it's the and and also he swims. Is it
the Zambzi? Um he he's swimming
>> like next to crocodiles and like every
morning and he like pushes them out of
the way like get out of the way you
[__] rascals and but the most to me
the it's it's completely you can't take
your eyes off it but the best moment for
me is there's a cabinet meeting and you
can hear the air conditioner like
rolling and he's going around the room
and it's kind of like got that sort of
East German kind of decor like you know
sort of that uh lives of others kind of
vibe and he's like okay So, Secretary of
Transport, Minister of Transportation,
um, sorry, Minister of Education, you're
doing good job. Keep it up. Uh, defense,
everything's looking good. He's going
around and he's like,
transportation.
And the guy starts quivering like a leaf
and he's like,
you know, the service in the still
getting complaints about the bus service
in the capital. Just, you have my
number, right? My four-digit number. And
he tells it like 3224.
You you I tell you you have a problem,
you call me morning, do and night, you
get it. Have you ever called me even one
time? You never call and nothing ever
gets better. And then the scene cuts and
there's the guy's body floating in the
river. It says the next day,
transportation minister so and so was
found floating in the Zambzi. I mean,
>> it's unbelievable. But anyway,
>> oh my god.
It's crazy. So, okay. Well, so does BB
Netanyahu, can he fly to Would the
Saudis take him in as a as the as could
they as the uh you know, prime minister
of a Jewish state?
>> Never.
>> Okay.
>> No. Never.
>> So, there's some decency. There are
limits. There are rules.
>> I You know what? I think that the reason
why they wouldn't ever do it is because
their own people would overthrow them.
Well, yeah,
>> they did something like that.
>> Yeah.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. No, he's more likely to end up,
you know, in in the US. I I was I was in
Oldtown Alexandria, Virginia one time.
Now, this is this is 20 years ago
and I saw Perves Musharif and his wife
just window shopping up and down King
Street.
It's like, so this is where you ended
up, you war criminal. Oh, he's a Yeah,
he's a he's a Yeah, I could go on about
him. Um, you know, because uh I've you
know, I'm a commentator. I don't really
break news. Um, the news that I broke
ever was the was the Perves Mashar coup.
Um, so I was down the street in
Islamabad uh at a cafe just eating and
um there was I'd just gotten down the
Kakorum Highway taking like three or
four weeks with my friend. Um, and so
we're like hanging out. We finally
arrived in Islamabad
and there's gunfire down the street and
uh, you know, small arms fire. And so I
asked the waiter, the waiters always
know everything. I said, "What's going
on?" He goes, "Oh, they are overthrowing
the the government." I'm like, "What?"
He goes, "Yeah, Omar Sharif, he is
finished. Like he's it's like they will
be killed." I'm like, "What?" It's like
I'm like, "Right now?" It's like, "Yeah,
that's them now." So, so I got up with
my camera and went and took a bunch of
photos and talked to some soldiers and
indeed like Omar Sharif in the van like
like while I'm talking outside I'm like
outside the van they're taking him off
to be tortured right they did torture
him and um so Perves Mashara uh you know
and I knew because when we came down the
the uh Kakorum highway we saw Taliban
soldiers all over the place in and you
know we were stopped at a checkpoint And
uh we're like and they're like, "Oh,
you're you're in Afghanistan." I'm like,
"This is the KKH. We're not in
Afghanistan. We're in Pakistan." And the
guy starts joking and he goes,
"Sometimes Afghanistan comes to you."
And um because Perves Musharif came to
power by as by with as an alliance with
the P with the with the Taliban and he
allowed the Taliban to enter northern
Afghan northern Pakistan to go as
proxies to go fight the Indians and
basically say we didn't attack you guys.
We don't know anything about it. It was
called the third Kashmir war with the
Cargill conflict. You know all this but
this is for the this is for the
audience.
>> Um
>> oh my god. And it's like, yeah, [__]
Perves Mashara. I mean, after 9/11,
right, Pakistan was still responsible
for what we they what happened to us
more than any other country. Did they
get justice? No. They got a raise.
>> Nope. That was it. They got a raise.
>> Yep. And like every exiled Pakistani
leader,
>> he's now in Dubai, which is exactly
where um
uh what was her name uh went. Um Prime
Minister uh
Oh, come on. We were just talking about
her last week. Why am I having a
>> Which country?
>> Pakistan.
>> Oh, BH Prime Minister BH and her
husband.
>> Yeah. back and forth between Pakistan
and Dubai, presidency and exile, you
know, crimes against humanity and all
that stuff.
>> Lovely fellows all around and ladies.
>> Yeah, she's dead. Musharv's dead.
They're all dead now.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's true.
>> She took a a bullet to the brain is what
did her in.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, that it is a I mean,
Pakistanis are spicy.
>> Oh, yeah. It's a tough It's a tough gig.
>> You don't want to cross them.
>> No, it's a tough gig. I mean it's like I
mean I I every moment I was in Pakistan
I had the feeling that a riot could
break out any second any second. Someone
who just could just walk down the street
and start screaming something in Erdo
and the next thing you know people are
out there with sticks and [__] and you
had guns out there like it's on and you
don't even know what's going on.
Um all right so all right where's Hamid
Carzai? Hamid Carzai is still in Kbble
living happily next to the Taliban. M's
got balls of steel, but
>> his brother's got a restaurant in
Baltimore if anyone wants to go check it
out. It's actually pretty good.
>> I do like Afghan food quite a bit. Um,
but well, not not the Afghan food there
for the most part, just because
>> the Afghan food in America is head and
shoulders better than any Afghan food.
>> It's like Cuban food. Cuban food sucks
in Cuba.
>> It's terrible in Cuba.
>> Yeah.
>> Like, how much zucchini can you eat?
>> Or boiled chicken. Yeah, tell me.
>> And and Bad Yellow Rice. Um,
all right. So,
>> what's your take on Immran Khan? I
actually like Imran Khan. I liked and
respected him. His problem is that
anytime he has a problem, whether it's
riots in the streets or an ingrown
toenail, he blames the United States.
>> I think we're gonna we're gonna leave
that that there for the deprogramming
for today. Um, just a reminder to
everybody in case you missed it. Um, it
would mean a lot to uh John and I and in
the most important way, which is to say
financially if you guys were to watch
this same exact show the same exact way
over on Rumble instead of YouTube. Um,
you know, obviously if you can't for
whatever reason, we love you on YouTube,
too. But, um, we get paid a zillion
times more over on Rumble than we do its
pennies on YouTube. There's no
comparison. So, um, you know, if you go
over to Rumble and just watch this
exactly the same way, it'd be much
appreciated. You don't have to remember
this weird URL. Just go to Rumble and
search for John or Eisen, my name or the
show andor the show, and it'll come
right up. And so, thank you very much.
We're here Monday, Wednesday, Friday,
five o'clock Eastern time. We're going
to be going in two weeks to a Monday
through Friday schedule, uh, 5:00 p. am.
So hopefully uh you guys will stick
around for that. We love this show and
we love you guys. We have the best fans
and the best watchers and viewers. So,
and we're fans of you guys, too. So,
it's a mutual admiration society. Um
anyway, John, always a pleasure. Hang in
there. And u
>> fun as it always is. It
>> It flies. Time flies. It does.
>> All right. And thanks everybody,
>> by the way. O Canada.
>> That's right. Kudos to the Canadians.